# **JORGEN BAERTSCH**

🗣 SEATTLE, WA, US 🗷 jpbaertsch@gmail.com 🛘 +1(218) 348-8032 🗖 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorgen-baertsch-8673b2142/

https://jpbaer.github.io/React-Portfolio/

### **SUMMARY**

As a highly skilled full-stack software engineer with 3 years of experience in aerospace systems, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and problem-solving skills to any project. With proficiency in multiple programming languages, including Python and JavaScript frameworks such as Node.Js, MongoDB and React, I am equipped to deliver cutting-edge solutions that exceed expectations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Recording/Mixing Engineer**

**Lost Boys Studios** 

August 2021 - Present, US, WA, Seattle

· Utilize a wide variety of hardware and software devices to record, edit, and mix audio to provide client's with a professional song that meets and exceeds industry expectations.

# **Aerospace Systems Engineer**

**Left Hand Design** 

June 2018 - March 2021, US, CO, Longmont

- · Aided in the development, procurement, and sale of Fast-Steering Mirrors for use in laser communication and defense systems.
- · Interfaced with customers to answer requests for information, develop system requirements, price tables and proposals leading in the generation of multiple contracts ranging from \$500,000 to \$5 million dollars.
- · Maintained assembly travelers and performed tests to ensure critical design requirements were being met.

## **PROIECTS**

### Project Manager/Backend Lead - Climate Change Impact App

- · Managed tasks and timelines for a team of 4 to develop a carbon footprint calculator that utilizes JavaScript, Node.JS, React, MongoDB, and GraphOL
- · Created GraphQL typeDefs and resolvers to define queries for retrieving user information and mutations for updating users carbon impacts based on various inputs
- · Pulled data from MongoDB database and displayed it graphically using Chart.JS
- · Incorporated a GPT chatbot on the applications "Learn" page using OpenAI API

# Project Manager/Backend Lead - Music Sharing Social Media App

March 2023 - March 2023

- · Successfully built application using Node. Js and SQL that integrates Spotify API our own REST API and database to pull and display users listening habits and playlists in social media like feed.
- · Developed feature for authentication, unique user profiles, messaging between users, and like and comment functionality.
- · Managed team of 4 using agile methodology for timelines and task delegation.

### Project Manager/Backend Lead - Real Estate App

February 2023 - February 2023

- · Developed a website using Javascript's Node. Js that utilizes an external real estate API to search cities and display current houses for sale.
- · Lead the integration of geo-location data from Google Maps API to fetch data from the real estate API at users location.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelors of Science In Aerospace Engineering**

University of Colorado at Boulder • US, Colorado, Boulder • 2018

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### **Full Stack Development Certification**

EdEx Bootcamps via University of Washington · 20232

Primary Skills Gained: React, NodeJs, SQL, MongoDB, Express, Javascript, HTML, CSS

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, Node.JS, SQL, MongoDB, React, HTML, CSS, Python, Git, REST API Development, GraphQL, Data Structures, Algorithms, System Design, Project Management, Docker, Jest, MVC, Microsoft Office